You came all this way
to the hot springs.
(カカシ)
で なんで お前がここにいるの？
You should take it easy
and stay a bit longer.
(ナルト)サクラちゃんが
カカシ先生のところに→
行くっつうから
ついてきちまった。
At any rate, I'm an impatient man.
There seems to be a storm
headed our way, so do be careful.
はぁ…。
Thank you very much
for everything.
I better hurry.
You're Tadaichi, a shinobi
of the Hidden Leaf, correct?
Well yes, I am from the Hidden Leaf.
But I wouldn't call myself a shinobi.
I'm just a lowly merchant.
You can't fool me.
I checked up on you and found out
what you did when were in the ANBU.
Visual Jutsu…?!
Beautifully done.
I'm going to stain everything red.
The Exploding Human
So, what are you doing here?
Sakura said she was coming
to see you, so I tagged along.
サクラは 何の用？
What is it, Sakura?
(サクラ)実は 木ノ葉の忍が→
There have been incidents of
Hidden Leaf shinobi going missing.
行方不明になる事件が
起きているんです。
Going missing?
行方不明？
うん。
サクラも気づいたか。
So you noticed it too, Sakura.
じゃあ カカシ先生も？
あぁ。
You were already aware of it,
Kakashi Sensei?
Yes. But why were you investigating
something like that?
しかし なんでまた
そんな事件のことを？
Well, there's a regular
at Ino's family's flower shop…
それが いのの実家の花屋の
常連さんが…。
(カカシ)あうんの門のほうか。
It's coming from the Aun Gate.
俺 行ってみるってばよ。
(カカシ/サクラ)あっ。
I'll go check it out, ya know!
Oh…
Wait, Naruto!
ナルト 待ちなさい！
おい ２人とも！
Hey, you two!
はぁ… 頼むぞ。
I'm counting on you.
Run! Get away from here!
逃げろ 逃げろ！
警備班だわ。
It's the Security Unit…
防戦一方じゃねえか。
Why are they only using defense?
手を貸すってばよ。
(いの)待って！
I'm gonna help 'em!
Wait!
いの… シカマル… チョウジ…。
Ino? Shikamaru…Choji?
どうしたの？
What happened?
ウソでしょ…。
It can't be…
(いの)タダイチさん。
(サクラ)え？
Mr. Tadaichi…
(いの)タダイチさんなの！
That's Mr. Tadaichi!
タダイチさんって
あんたが言ってた花屋の常連の？
Mr. Tadaichi?
You mean your regular
from the flower shop?
(シカマル)間違いねえのか？ いの。
Are you sure that's him, Ino?
There's no mistake!
間違えっこないわ！
でも 木ノ葉に
牙をむくような人じゃない。
But he'd never turn against
the Hidden Leaf!
どうして…。
So why?
だとしたら
幻術にかかってる可能性が→
So does that mean…
there's a possibility
he's under genjutsu?
あんのか？
みんな 行方不明になっていた
人たちかも。
And the others could be
the ones who went missing!
What?!
なんだって!?
(チョウジ)じゃあ→
Then…these are Hidden Leaf shinobi?
木ノ葉の忍ってこと？
だから防戦を強いられてんのか。
That's why we can't do
anything other than defend!
よけもしなかった。
He didn't even dodge.
痛みも感じていない？
Doesn't he feel any pain?
やべえ… 影分身の術！
This is bad!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ナルト!?
飛ぶぞ。
Naruto?!
We're gonna jump away.
まるで起爆人間だってばよ。
He's an exploding human!
(いの)タダイチさん…。
Mr. Tadaichi…
大丈夫。
It's okay.
負傷者の手当てを。
Let's go tend to the wounded.
おい 入ってきちまったぞ。
Hey!
They're getting in!
Not…them too!
まさか あいつらも？
It's too big!
でかすぎだってばよ。
チッ。
Damn!
Choji…
チョウジ 倍加で羽出せるか？
Can you bring out your wings
with your expansion?
わ わかった。
G-Got it!
うぉ～！
I'll help!
加勢するぜ。 いくぞ 九喇嘛！
Let's go, Kurama!
Right!
うぉ～！
ハァ ハァ… なんとかなったのかな？
Did…it help at all?
さすがだぜ。
Good job!
Looks like it ain't over yet.
いや
終わってねえみてえだってばよ。
(シカマル)まだいやがったのか。
There are more of them.
ナルト。
Naruto!
Getting wounded is probably
what causes them to explode.
あいつらが爆発するきっかけは
たぶん 傷よ。
傷口から
奇妙なチャクラが放出されて→
I saw strange chakra being
released from the wound,
体の変形が始まっていたわ。
and the body began
to change shape.
Which means,
そうなると
うかつには手を出せねえぞ。
we have to be careful
how we engage them.
(ヒナタ)ナルト君！
ヒナタ。
Naruto!
Hinata!
何が起きてるの？
What's happening?
みんな
幻術かけられてるみてえなんだ。
It seems everyone's under
a genjutsu.
どっかに操ってるやついねえか？
Can you see if
someone's controlling them?
わかった 調べてみる。
All right, I'll check.
白眼！
Byakugan!
いないみたい。
いないの？
I don't see anyone.
No one?!
だったら
どうやって操ってるの？
Then how are they being manipulated?
(ヒナタ)あの人たちの体の中に
特殊なチャクラが巡ってる。
There's a strange chakra
moving around in their bodies.
それが操ってるのかも。
Maybe that's what's controlling them.
じゃあ そのチャクラを
取っちまえばいいのか。
So we just have to take
that chakra away?
チャクラは体の一部みたいに巡ってる。
The chakra is circulating like
it's part of their body.
体内で融合してるかもしれない。
The chakra could be fused internally.
つまり 簡単に引き剥がすことは
できねえってことか。
So you're saying
we can't just peel it away easily.
ひとまず 相手を捕獲する
ところから始めねえとな。
First things first.
We have to start
by capturing them.
でも シカマル ケガをさせずに
捕獲するのは難しいわよ。
But Shikamaru,
it'll be hard to capture them
without inflicting any wounds.
いい案 思いついたってばよ！
I just had a great idea!
うぁ～！
そんじゃ いくぜ！
Okay, let's go!
First, I'll have my clones
stop the exploding humans.
＜ まずは 俺が影分身で
起爆人間の足を止める＞
影真似の術！
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
＜ そんでシカマルが
影真似の術で捕獲＞
Then Shikamaru will capture them
with his Shadow Possession Jutsu.
ヒナタ！
はい！
Hinata!
Right!
And lastly, Hinata will pierce
their critical chakra points
＜最後はヒナタが急止の点穴を突いて
動けなくする＞
so that they can't move.
一日は動けないはずよ。
They won't be able to move
for a day.
大丈夫か ヒナタ。
You okay, Hinata?
うん 一緒に戦うよ。
Yes.
I'll fight with you.
ダメです。 私の幻術返しじゃ→
It's no good.
My Genjutsu Reversal has
no effect against
体の中を巡る 特殊なチャクラは
どうすることも…。
the special kind of chakra
circulating in the body.
まっ そう落ち込むな。
Don't get so depressed.
誰がやったにしろ
未知の幻術が使われている。
Whoever did it,
that's a genjutsu unknown to us.
相当な腕を持つ
幻術使いの仕業だろう。
It has to be the work of someone
with extraordinary skill.
優れた瞳術を持つ者が
対応すべきだね。
So it will require someone
with exceptional Visual Jutsu powers.
(サイ)瞳術？
Visual Jutsu?
ご明察！
Good observation!
私 まだ何も言ってません！
I-I didn't say anything!
え？
何を言ってないんだってばよ。
Didn't say what?
聞くな！
ナルト君！
Don't ask!
Naruto!
俺たちには見えないことも→
We may not be able to see anything.
写輪眼と輪廻眼を持つ
あいつの目には→
But the one who possesses both
the Sharingan and Rinnegan just might.
映るかもしれない。
えっ!? ってことは…。
Huh?! You mean…?
サスケを呼び戻す。
I'll call Sasuke back.
頼めるかな。
はい。
Can I ask you to do it?
Yes.
サスケが帰ってくる。
Sasuke's gonna come back!
I am all alone.
((サスケ : 俺は１人だ。
I alone can bear the weight
of all the hatred now.
もう すべての憎しみを
１人だけで背負うことができる。
You don't have a clue about
how Itachi lived!
(お前は イタチの生きざまも
わかっちゃいねえ！))
Why do all that just
to get in my way?
((そんなになってまで
なぜ 俺の邪魔をしたがる？
友達だからだ。
‘Cuz you're my friend.
I've heard that before.
それは かつて聞いた。
But what exactly does that mean?
お前にとっての それは
いったい なんなんだ？
正直 俺も よくわからねえよ。
You ask me to explain it,
but I really can't put it into words.
ただ お前のそういう→
It's just that…
when I see you take on stuff
and get all messed up…
背負って
ゴチャゴチャしてるとこ見てっと→
なんでか→
It…
kinda…
(俺が痛ぇんだ))
hurts me.
「木ノ葉に戻れ」 か…。
Return to the Hidden Leaf Village, huh?
(イオウ)あ… うわ～！
(イオウ)人間が爆発しよった！
A human exploded!
チクショウ！
よせ！
D-Damn you!
Stop!
Don't tell me
that's the exploding human
まさか… 今のが
木ノ葉を襲ったという起爆人間!?
that attacked the Hidden Leaf?!
なぜ こんな村に…。
Why? A village like this?
Old Man Iou!
(チノ)イオウのじいちゃん！
あ… あぁ…。
Chino, stall them.
(ノワキ)チノ！ 足止めを。
(チノ)任せて！ ノワキ。
You got it, Nowaki!
水遁 水陣壁の術！
Water Style: Water Formation Wall!
忍？
Shinobi?
これは いったい 何の騒ぎだ？
What's going on?
W-What?!
な… なんじゃ!?
お前も あいつらの仲間か？
Are you one of them?
人違いだ。
You've got it all wrong.
Silence!
黙れ！ やつに頼まれて 仕返しを
見届けにきたんじゃろうが!!
They asked you to come
and get even, didn't they?
仕返し？
Get even?
Young ones!
What are you doing?
若造ども！ 何をしとる!?
Damn it!
ったく もう…。
ごめん！ 何の恨みもないけど…。
Sorry, I don't have anything
against you, but…
水遁！
Water Style…
Rain Hail!
雨あられ！
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
火遁 豪火球の術！
What?!
え～っ！ 水遁が火遁に
押し負けることって あるの!?
I didn't know Fire Style
could beat Water Style!
Get back.
下がっていろ。
風の性質変化か。
A Change in Nature of Wind, huh?
かはっ!? え～い！
さっさと殺さんかい!!
Oh, come on!
Hurry up and kill him!
え～っ！
あんなに強いって聞いてないし。
No one told me
he was so strong!
え～い！ この根性なしどもが!!
You spineless—!
ヒ… ヒィーッ！
俺を誰かと勘違いした理由
あとで聞かせてもらうぞ。
You can tell me later why
you mistook me for someone else.
あの目…。
That eye…
写輪眼…。
The Sharingan?!
うちは…。
Uchiha…
Why did the villagers end up like this?
村人たちが
こうなってしまった理由は？
How should I know?!
わしが知るか！
The one you mistook me for
is involved in some way, right?
俺と勘違いした誰かが
関わっているんだな？
言いとうないわ！
I've got nothing to say!
ご ごめん 私らも
何がなんだか…。
I-I'm sorry.
We don't know
what's going on either.
From the looks of it,
you're not from this village, are you?
見たところ
この村の人間じゃなさそうだな。
うん。 私たちは
忍くずれの旅芸人でね。
We're former shinobi
who are now traveling performers.
We finished a gig at a resort
この先にある湯隠れの温泉街で
ひと儲けしてきたんだよ。
in the Village Hidden
in the Hot Springs.
あそこじゃ娯楽は
金になるからね。
It's pretty profitable there
for entertainers like us.
Anyway…
(チノ)んで また違う土地に
行こうかってんで→
We decided to head somewhere else,
食料調達に この竹ノ村を
通りかかったんだけどさ。
so we came through the Bamboo Village
to stock up on supplies.
いや～
イオウのじいちゃんの娘さんが→
And Old Man Iou's daughter
is such a great person!
できた人でさあ！
フン！
おいしいごはんは
ご馳走してくれるし…。
She made us really good food!
そうじゃ 娘は…
アミノは無事か？
By the way, is my daughter…
Is Amino okay?
アミノ～！
Amino!
そうそう 女子供は
避難させてたんだよ。
We had all the women and
children take shelter…
お～い。
Hey!
こいつらに直接
聞いてみるしかないようだな。
We have no choice
but to ask these guys directly.
(女子供たち)キャー！
ああ アミノ。
Amino?!
起爆人間!?
An exploding human?!
イオウさん 近寄ると危ない。
Mr. Iou, don't go near.
It's too dangerous.
って 誰が危ないもんか！
あれはな わしの娘じゃ！
Who cares if it's dangerous?!
That's my daughter!
離せ 離さんか～！
Let go… Let me go!
ああっ アミノ～！
Amino!
許さん…。
I'll never forgive you.
許さんぞ 風心。
Never…Fuushin…
許さんぞ～ 風心め～！
I'll never forgive you, Fuushin!
風心とは誰だ？
Who is Fuushin?
雷光団の頭です。
The leader of the Lightning Gang.
雷光団？
The Lightning Gang?
雷光団は→
They take money from bad people
あくどい連中から
巻き上げた金品を→
我らのような貧しいもんに
配ってくれた義賊です。
and distribute it
to poor people like us.
They're honorable thieves.
その頭が どうして仕返しを？
So why would their leader
try to get even?
き 聞いた話です。
This is just what I heard…
雷光団は
霧隠れの裏切りにあったそうです。
The Lightning Gang was betrayed
by the Hidden Mist…
風心たちは 命からがら→
It seems they barely escaped
with their lives
この村まで逃げて来たそうです。
and found their way to this village.
((風心 : いっときでいい
休ませてくれ！
Just for a little while…
Let us rest here.
(イオウ)よそに行ってくれ。
え？
Please go somewhere else.
What?
お前たちを匿ったら わしらまで
被害を被るかもしれん。
む 村に迷惑をかけるつもりはない
すぐに出ていく！
他人から巻き上げた金を
配っただけで→
(よく ぬけぬけと
そんなことが言えるな))
村は 雷光団を捨てたんです。
どうするの？
起爆人間の記憶を覗く。
え？
うお～！
大丈夫？
あの赤眼。
間違いない。
血継限界だ。